HADEN WATNE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER



ABOUT ME

IT professional specializing in fullstack software development for web applications.

Familiar with Agile, Angular, C#, CI/CD, CSS, Git, HTML, Java, JavaScript, JSON, LEAN, .NET, Node, Python, PWAs, React, ReactiveX, SCRUM, Splunk, SPAs, SQL, TypeScript, Unit Testing, and XML.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS

CCU • 2015 - 2019 Magna Cum Laude

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

CCU • 2015 - 2019 Magna Cum Laude

CERTIFICATIONS

SQL SERVER 2016 - DATABASE DEVELOPMENT (MCSA)

Earned in November 2018

PROGRAMMING IN C#

Microsoft Exam 483 Earned in April 2018

PROGRAMMING IN HTML5, JAVASCRIPT, AND CSS3

Microsoft Exam 480 Earned in May 2017

NETWORKING FUNDAMENTALS

Microsoft Exam 98-366 Earned in May 2017

EXPERIENCE

PROGRESSIVE INSURANCE

June 2019 - Present

Software engineer on an Agile development team for a high-traffic & full-stack web application. Code development, mentorship, stability monitoring, and corporate compliance are key responsibilities.

Senior IT Apps Programmer

October 2022 - Present

- Improved developer habits and planning processes on a newly formed Scrum team.
- Led a transition project for our application to use new PCI compliance guidelines.
- Integrated our REST API with the IVR phone system to enable more payment options.
- Seamlessly connected our mobile app and our TypeScript frontend for enhanced UX.
- Completed planning for customer-facing UI improvements displaying flow progress.

IT Apps Programmer

February 2021 - October 2022

- Developed new API endpoints for IVR users to cancel their policy over the phone.
- Refactored and improved the stability of our company's largest user payment screen.
- Created Splunk monitoring tools used widely during on-call production support.

Associate IT Apps Programmer

June 2019 - February 2021

- Designed an automated analytics report read daily by 200+ leaders and developers.
- Invested in new IT interns through the Intern Ambassador program.
- Delivered the Angular components for enrolling customers in automatic payments.

IT Intern

May 2018 - August 2018

- Modernized an ASP.NET web application to improve usability for vehicle lienholders.
- Updated internal documentation for multiple applications.
- Completed a 3-month group research project on emerging autonomous vehicles.

CUBEDHOST, LLC

January 2016 - June 2019

Customer support technician for an online, worldwide, virtual private server hosting service. Investigated software conflicts and bare metal performance to correct problems.

Server Support Specialist

January 2016 - June 2019

- Connected with clients to troubleshoot server performance.
- Debugged console errors, system behavior, and software dependencies.
- Analyzed systems to determine network congestion, resource usage, and stability.